MOUSA AL-SHEHAB

SENIOR PRE-SALES CONSULTANT

Experience in the design and implementation of complex IT solutions (including scalable cloud-based solutions and microservices architectures). Excellent communication and leadership capabilities. Great experience and knowledge in advanced technologies in Cloud Computing, Software Defined technologies, Networking, Wireless, Security, Administrations and Infrastructures.

MOBILE: 0500999823 EMAIL: SHEHABM1@GMAIL.COM







SYSTEM ADMINISTRATIONS

CLOUD COMPUTING &

CONTAINERIZATION

MARKETING & ECOMMERCE

MIGRATION & DISASTER

RECOVERY

PRESALES & LEADERSHIP

RFP, RFI, RFQ RESPONSE

PRICING, QUOTATIONS & SOW

CLOUD MIGRATION

STRATEGIES

PROOF OF CONCEPTS POCS

WORK EXPERIENCE

PRESALES CLOUD CONSULTANT, VIRTUAL VISION V2, 01/2022 - PRESENT

- Assess & Design infrastructure and technology platforms, including operating systems, compute, Storage, Data Center networks, virtualization, Data Protection, databases, cloud-based and Internet-related tools.
- Responsible for identifying, and documenting technical solution, risks, costs, creating solutions that to meet customer, contract, and deployment requirements.
- SME for public cloud (AWS & Azure), VMware cloud solutions, and cloud migration technology domains.
- Make decisions based on scope of the deal and possible trade-offs to best meet client's objectives within the limits necessary to win the contract.
- Lead the managed services for Security such as SIEM, SOC and Firewalls and provide it as a service
- Created migration strategies to bridge development gaps between existing software architecture and
- future updates.
- Identified sales opportunities by assessing environment and devising and implementing winning strategy.
- Determines hardware compatibility and/or influences hardware design.

PROJECT MANAGER, WIPRO LTD, 2011 - 2022

- Mentoring and technical leadership through active communication of the architecture and assisting developers with detailed design, implementation and testing
- Contribute with the largest organizations in the region such as Saudi Aramco, SABIC and SEC for at diversity filed of technologies like ERP systems, System Administrations and Infrastructure.
- Led IT team across variety of projects by providing High Level Design, BOQ, Technical Proposals, Network Diagram, and the required consultancy.
- Provide support to secure and deliver reports related to business and projects performance to the senior level management.
- Responsible end to end to get the projects successful by coordinate with internal resources and third parties/vendors for the flawless execution of multiple projects
- · Identifying staff development and training needs and putting together bespoke training pack for them.

SAP TRAINEE, ALBILAD ALARABIYA, 2010 - 2011

- Get hands on training about ERP Systems development and enroll at first development projects.
- Fix software bugs, develop applications performance and respond to End-user tickets to get resolved.

IT SUPPORT ENGINEER, NIZAK ENGINEERING SYSTEMS, MAR -2009 - 2010

- Get hands on training about ERP Systems development and enroll at first development projects.
- Fix software bugs, develop applications performance and respond to End-user tickets to get resolved.

MOUSA AL-SHEHAB

SENIOR PRE-SALES CONSULTANT

MOBILE: 0500999823

EMAIL: SHEHABM1@GMAIL.COM

ADDITIONAL SKILLS & EXPERTISE

AMINISTRATIONS

- Experience in Windows & Linux (and UNIX)
 operating systems in server environments.
- Setting up and installing computers, networks, and software.
- Manages upgrades and implements security controls.
- Server Patch deployment and troubleshooting and resolving Server operating systems-related technical problems.
- Monitoring System status, usage, and performance and maintaining Tuning systems, cleanup, and resource management.
- Building and maintaining deployment and infrastructure automation tools.
- Administer server utilities such as File Servers & Print Servers including installation, managing users' shares and permissions, observing file growth and troubleshooting user access problems.
- Conduct surveys and research to identify areas that require improvement and ways to achieve desired improvement

ERP -SAP (ECC - S4 HANA)

- Long term experience with SAP developments projects with Saudi Aramco, SABIC and SEC.
- Develop ERP applications (SAP ABAP Programs) and dealing with different SAP Modules.
- Upgrade SAP applications and transactions from ECC to S4 HANA,
- Experience in SAP UI5, FIORI, ODATA services, CRM, ITSM configuration, role assignment. and administer related basis activities.

CLOUD COMPUTING & CONTAINERIZATIONS

- well knowledge and able to deal with cloud computing services like AWS and Azure.
- Understanding the benefits of the digital transformation for private cloud and public cloud.
- Dealing and understanding new container technologies like Docker, Kubernates and openshift.
- Cloud, DevOps, Mobile, business Process Management, and Hybrid Integration; Software, Cloud Services (laaS, PaaS and SaaS)
- Interfacing and managing vendors, third-party partner resources, contractors and other suppliers.
- Design the best fit solution based on clients requirement in terms of cost, Security and High Availability.
- Reached and contacted with multiple 3rd party vendors for most complexity projects for security and load balancing and other solution.
- Backup & DR as a service plan management.

MARKETING & ECOMMERCE

- Web design using different web platform and administer websites/portals
- Prepare the web with UI design best practices.
- Social Media marketing, SEO Analysis, PPC campaign.
- Market research and identify the opportunities and find the relevant keywords and marketing strategies

EDUCATION & AWARDS

UNIVERSITY OF PORTSMOUTH

Bachelor in Business Information Systems, 2014

SHAW ACADEMY

Diploma in photography, 2016

JUBIAL INDUSTRIAL COLLEGE

Diploma in Information Technology 2009

IELTS ENGLISH 2021

Cambridge Assessment Test Band 6.0

AWS CERTIFIED

Amazon Cloud Practitoner CLF-C01 -2019

SAP SYSTEMS CERTIFIED

SAP NetWeaver Development 2010